Joshua Daniel Lawsin

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

I am a software developer with nearly two years of experience in front-end and back-end development in web applications. I have experience working with different tech stacks, where I primarily collaborated with my previous company's Japanese counterparts on various projects. I am a passionate learner, committed to continually expanding my knowledge in this ever-evolving technology field. In my previous company, I have showcased my ability to deliver high-quality results and the ability to adapt and understand things I have yet to experience or work on. Software development is an exciting journey where there's always something new to discover and learn.

Employment History

Associate Software Engineer - Intern, Lanex Corporation, Cebu City

AUGUST 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

Throughout my internship training, I actively participated in the entire process of our internal project. I received comprehensive training in soft and technical skills. Here's a summary of my experiences:

- Proposed Features
- · Design Low and High-Fidelity Designs
- Design and develop front-end
- Consistently part of the overall planning, designing, and development of the project
- Review merge request from co-interns
- Used Google Sheets as a headless CMS for the project
- Used MirageJS as Mockup API

Software Development Engineer, Lanex Corporation, Cebu City

JANUARY 2023 - AUGUST 2024

Throughout my tenure, I primarily collaborated with our Japanese counterparts on various projects. Specifically, I worked on three client projects in Japan and one internal project. In summary, my role was to:

- Create and maintain visually appealing and user-friendly web interfaces.
- Collaborate with designers to implement intuitive and engaging user experiences.
- Develop server-side logic and database queries using C#, Javascript, and PHP.
- Design database
- Optimize web applications
- Bug fixing
- Stay updated with the latest web development trends, tools, and technologies.
- Create and maintain code documentation, API's and development processes.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems, University of San Carlos - Talamban Campus, Cebu City

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2023

Senior High School (STEM Strand), University of Cebu - Banilad Campus, Cebu City

AUGUST 2016 - MARCH 2018

Details

Block 3 Lot 11 Villa Ventura, Bagong dan, Yati, Liloan Cebu, 6002 Philippines 09953827955 jdlawsin@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://joshua-lawsin.vercel.app

Skills HTML

CSS

Sass

TailwindCSS

Bootstrap

Javascript

jQuery

ReactJS NextJS

Ant-design

MaterialUI

ChakraUI

NodeJS

ExpressJS

NestJS

C#

.Net wep api

NPOI

Python

Flask

РНР

Laravel

PostgreSQL

MySQL

Certificates

Certificate of Participation and Recognition, Davao City

NOVEMBER 2022 - NOVEMBER 2022

Attended and presented our paper entitled "Memores: A Web-Based Intelligent Screening Tool for Predicting Social Anxiety Disorder using a Machine Learning Model" for the conference ICITE 2022 at Mapúa Malayan Colleges Mindanao.

Awards

Best Presenter Award, Davao City

NOVEMBER 2022 - NOVEMBER 2022

Our team won the best presenter award for presenting our paper, "Memores: A Web-Based Intelligent Screening Tool for Predicting Social Anxiety Disorder using a Machine Learning Model," at ICITE 2022 at Mapúa Malayan Colleges Mindanao.

References

Neftali Papelleras, Senior Software Engineer from Sansan Global Development Company (SGDC)

papelleras.nef@gmail.com | 09329195661

John Pierre Cena, Senior Software Engineer from Lanex Corporation pierre@lanexcorp.com | 09616509505

Ed Garate, Junior Software Engineer from Lanex Corporation ed.kenneth11@gmail.com | 09284305193

MsSQL Dbeaver Postman Git GitHub GitLab Backlog JIRA Figma LucidChart Slack Languages Cebuano Filipino English